ABDULLAH HASSAN

Data Analyst | Workstation Support Tech

(615) 788-0930 Abdullahissack@outlook.com/linkedin.com/in/abdullah-hassan-/|github.com/Abdullah0930

Professional Summary:

With my background as a Workstation Support Specialist, I've been keen in being able to make better decisions by way of Data Analytics. Therefore, I've decided to combine my previous experience at TN State along with my passion for Data by re-educating myself through Nashville Software School's Data Analytics Program. I believe that the tools and skills I have learned through NSS along with customer service experience to go from Data Insights to better business decisions.

Key Skills/ Abilities:

- Data Analysis, Microsoft Power BI, Tableau, Python (Pandas, seaborn, REs), Excel (Pivot, VLOOKUP), GitHub
- SQL (PostgreSQL, Modeling, Joining Datasets etc.) Workstation Support, Service-Now, Attention to detail

Professional Experience:

Nashville Software School, Data Analytics Apprentice January 2021 to Present

Nashville Software School, Data Analytics Jumpstart October 2020

Intensive data analytics program offering hands-on training that provides deep understanding of core data analytics.

Excel Project- Worked with data cleaning, Pivot Tables, VLOOKUP etc. on 500 Monthly searches for Metro.

SQL Project- My part of SQL project using PostgreSQL (Queries, Aggregation, Joins, Sanity check etc.)

Tableau Project- Group Project using Data Modeling, cleaning, captivating Dashboards etc.

State of Tennessee

July 2017 to Present

Workstation Support Specialist

- Helpdesk support Agent for issues related to Hardware/Software up to 15 users a day.
- Responsible for configuration and deployment of various agency Laptop/PCs, printers etc.
- Responsible for submitting warranty repairs various state agencies electronic equipment's.
- Utilize ticketing system SERVICE-NOW to accept or submit between 5-10 requests daily.
- Contact Customers right away to resolve issues or escalate the incident/Task to different team.
- Troubleshoot and provide resolutions on timely manner or escalate/reassigning requests etc.
- Assist with telecommunications support (VoIP/Sisco Telephony), Jabber, WebEx, audio.
- Perform local backup procedures for various state agencies when customers get new device.
- Grants approved access to agency applications for system access and security levels.
- Identify and analyzes equipment for inventory management and coordinates surplus efforts.

FedEx

May 2017 to July 2017

Supply Chain ERP Systems Support (Temp)

- · Troubleshoot and diagnosed hardware and software issues for a various new equipment.
- systems ordered by various companies in an effective and timely manner before shipment.
- Configured and tested system functionality making sure input and outputs are accurate.
- Replaced system hardware parts / Configure BIOS, RAID, iRAC etc. on Dell equipment.

Education:

Nashville Software School, Data Analytics Bootcamp Graduating June 2021

Tennessee State University, B.B.A in Info. Systems May 7, 2016

Community Involvement:

- Volunteered at Harpeth River watershed and Second Harvest Food Bank.
- Volunteered at Nashville Rescue Mission for the Feed the Homeless program.
- Love to Mentor and play ball with youth in community mainly in summer times.
- Recently Volunteered at my local community mass food and vaccination drives.